JONATHAN WINDLE

■ jonathan.p.windle@gmail.com ★ jonathanpwindle.github.io

J 07539901984 jonathanpwindle

Jonathan Windle

in jonathanpwindle

I am an experienced researcher specialising in Multimodal Generative AI. I have spent five years in academia contributing cutting-edge work to a variety of publications. As my PhD comes to an end, I want to bring my exprience with AI into an industry role.

RELEVANT SKILLS

EDUCATION

Machine Learning Tools PyTorch NumPy | SciKit-Learn

Pandas Weights & Biases

HuggingFace

Programming Languages

₽Τ_ΕΧ Python Java C C++

Development Tools

Git Trello Docker PhD in Artificial Intelligence (expected)

University of East Anglia

Oct 2020 - Present

Thesis title: Digital Humans: Automatic Character Animation

Expected thesis submission April 2024

Expected viva date pending

B.Sc. Hons: Computing Science with a year in industry

First Class

University of East Anglia

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

EXPERIENCE

Postgraduate Researcher

University of East Anglia

Ct 2020 - Present

During this time I worked in UEA's Computer Science department to complete my PhD. My research focus is Digital **Humans: Automatic Character Animation**

- Developed cutting-edge Multimodal Generative AI models for speech-to-animation, including diffusion models
- Achieved competitive results in two successive Generation and Evaluation of Non-verbal Behaviour for Embodied Agents Challenges
- Harnessed Large Language Model (LLM) features to produce high-quality outputs
- Engaged at length with generative modelling best practices through paper reviews and library documentation
- Exhibited a high standard of technical communication and an ability to adapt stylistically to the needs of differrent publications, conference talks, and guest lectures
- Independently developed AI engineering and experimental procedures by tracking experiment performance and model optimisation using tools such as Weights and Biases
- Performed extensive subjective and objective evaluation using advanced techniques such as Frechet Distances and pair-wise statistical analysis
- Multimodal data analysis and exploration resulting in journal publication
- Assisted welcoming external researchers to the BMVA summer school

Research Associate

University of East Anglia

i Jun 2019 - September 2020

Worked within the UEA Computer Science department assisting with research in user identification using keystroke

- Designed successful machine learning experiments for user identification using keystroke dynamics
- Fully understood and implemented appropriate ethical procedure regarding the implications of AI and human user study
- Developed a full-stack online data-gathering platform and data-processing pipeline for use on multiple datasets
- Productively collaborated with other research groups with internal and external research groups

Software Developer Intern

Boeing Defence UK

Jul 2017 - Sep 2018

Completed a year long placement with Boeing Defence UK, gaining exposure to a variety of departments and work processes including its industry leading R&D department

- Delivered business-critical software to the Ministry of Defence
- · Worked on prototype software for automated object detection using multimodal data

- Worked on a full-stack website development project with continual positive client feedback
- Praised for ability to adapt quickly to new environments and projects as they were assigned
- Developed quick code implementation, prototyping and experimental skills
- Experienced requirements gathering and current landscape analysis
- Employee Involvement vice-captain. A leader in encouraging good team practices, active team involvement, improvements and cost reduction initiatives

Associate Tutor

University of East Anglia

Sep 2019 - Present

Assisted in teaching both undergraduate and postgraduate modules including AI, Architectures & Operating Systems, Ubiquitous Computing, Programming and Data Structures and Algorithms.

- Assisted students in Laboratory sessions, delivering informative presentations and providing constructive feedback, inlcuding marking coursework to tight deadlines
- Receieved positive feedback for concise and insightful explanation of advanced topics

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

- J. Windle, I. Matthews, and S. Taylor, "Llanimation: Llama driven animation," ACM Trans. Graph., 2024, CURRENTLY UNDER REVIEW.
- O. Buckley, D. Hodges, J. Windle, and S. Earl, "Clicka: Collecting and leveraging identity cues with keystroke dynamics," Computers & Security, vol. 120, p. 102 780, 2022.
- J. Windle, S. Taylor, D. Greenwood, and I. Matthews, "Arm motion symmetry in conversation," *Speech Communication*, vol. 144, pp. 75–88, 2022, ISSN: 0167-6393. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.specom.2022.08.001.

Conference Proceedings

- J. Windle, I. Matthews, and S. Taylor, "Style conditioned speech-to-gesture generation with long-term context," in *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision*, **CURRENTLY UNDER REVIEW**, 2024.
- J. Windle, I. Matthews, B. Milner, and S. Taylor, "The uea digital humans entry to the genea challenge 2023," in *Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Multimodal Interaction*, ser. ICMI '23, Paris, France: Association for Computing Machinery, 2023, pp. 802–810, ISBN: 9798400700552. DOI: 10.1145/3577190.3616116.
- J. Windle, D. Greenwood, and S. Taylor, "Uea digital humans entry to the genea challenge 2022," in *Proceedings of the 2022 International Conference on Multimodal Interaction*, ser. ICMI '22, Bengaluru, India: Association for Computing Machinery, 2022, pp. 771–777, ISBN: 9781450393904. DOI: 10.1145/3536221.3558065.
- J. Windle, S. Taylor, D. Greenwood, and I. Matthews, "Pose augmentation: Mirror the right way," in *Proceedings of the 22nd ACM International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents*, ser. IVA '22, Faro, Portugal: Association for Computing Machinery, 2022, ISBN: 9781450392488. DOI: 10.1145/3514197.3549677.
- S. Taylor, J. Windle, D. Greenwood, and I. Matthews, "Speech-driven conversational agents using conditional flow-vaes," in *Proceedings of the 18th ACM SIGGRAPH European Conference on Visual Media Production*, ser. CVMP '21, London, United Kingdom: Association for Computing Machinery, 2021, ISBN: 9781450390941. DOI: 10.1145/3485441.3485647.